如果我把整罐橄榄吃光 你要给我多少钱？
How much you give me to eat this whole jar of olives?
我一块钱也不给 但你欠我两块九毛五
I won't give you anything,but you'll owe me $2.95.
成交
Done.
我需要地图…
I need an atlas! I need an atlas!
干嘛？你要交报告？
Why? Do you have a report due?
我昨天在联合国外做免费按摩 认识一个外交官
I have a date with diplomat I met...
我要跟他约会
...while I was giving free massages outside the U. N.
我不知道他是哪个国家的人
And I don't know where his country is.
先说你为什么要在联合国 做免费按摩服务
Let's start with the free massages at the U.N.
这是我的新目标，我认为 平和的身体可以缔造和平
It's my new thing. I figure,"Bodies at peace make peace."
你搞不好会得第一座 诺贝尔按摩奖
You might just get the first Nobel Prize in rubbing.
这家伙是哪个国家的人？
So what country is this guy from?
里面有个“G”
There's a "g" in there.
这个国家在哪里？
Where's that?
在你的地图上
In your atlas!
我没有地图
I don't have an atlas.
不过等等 我有地球仪，等一下
But wait,I do have a globe. Hold on.
他是什么样的人？
So what's this guy like?
他很…
Well,he's very...
有冲劲
...dashing,you know?
而且非常老练
And very,very sophisticated.
他不会讲英文
And he doesn't speak English...
但他的翻译说 他对我意乱情迷
... but his translator says he totally gets me.
好，来了
Okay,here you go.
这是什么？
What is this?
地球仪
It's a globe.
也是削铅笔机
And a pencil sharpener.
地球上的人们，投降吧  巨大的外星人 五个小脑袋
People of Earth, surrender.Giant alien.Five tiny heads.
有什么要影印的吗？ 我要到影印店去
Need anything copied? I'm going to the Xerox place.
不用了，谢谢
No,thanks.
随便给我什么拿去影印就好
Just give me anything I can make two of.
如果你没有东西要影印 干嘛要去？
If you have nothing to copy,why go there?
你又要去看那个…
Are you just gonna gawk at that girl...
钉了肚脐环的女孩？
...with the bellybutton ring again?
要一起去吗？
You wanna come?
本集播出： “罗斯和瑞秋分手”
The One Where Ross and Rachel Take a Break
快，克萝伊 先把你的顾客解决掉
Come on,Chloe. Finish with your customer first.
快点，克萝伊…
Come on,Chloe. Come on,Chloe!
要影印吗？
Can I help you?
我们改变主意了
We're having second thoughts about our copying needs.
还需要时间考虑要影印什么
And we'll need more time to think about it.
克萝伊，跟我换 有人迷上你了
Chloe,switch with me. Some guys have a crush on you.
好，真是伤人
Okay,that hurt us.
我从早上就没看见你们了
Hi,guys. I haven't seen you since this morning.
这个嘛…
Well...
你知道…
...you know.
你们明天有事吗？
What are you doing tomorrow?
我们两个？
Both of us?
也许吧，害怕了吗？
Maybe. Does that scare you?
别紧张，艾塞克在 菲力酒吧当DJ
Relax. Isaac's deejaying at The Philly.
你们应该来听听看 我们会的
-You should come. -We'll be there.
太好了，到时候见
Great. I'll see you then.
好啊，摇摇摇
All right! Rock on.
他说和你散步，让他觉得 仿佛这个城就是他的家
He says that walking with you makes this strange city feel like home.
我也是，虽然这里 本来就是我家
Me too. Although this city is my home.
我说的是蠢话 别跟他说我说的
So that's dumb,what I said. Don't tell him I said that.
你自己乱翻吧
You make something up.
很好，谢谢
Nice! Thank you.
我家到了
This is me,here.
你的眼睛好美
Your eyes are very pretty.
非常谢谢你
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Oh,thank you.
他想吻你
He would like to kiss you.
你不必麻烦了
You don't have to do that now.
不，我不是说他 不，是你不必麻烦了
No,no,not him! No,you don't.
时机已经过了
The moment's over.
就在这里
There it is,right there.
好小
It's small.
对，但塞尔吉说 德军花了六星期
Yeah,but Sergei said it took the Germans six weeks...
才横跨国境
...to get all the way across it.
你开心吗？
So you had fun?
只可惜约会的时候…
Except for,you know,when you're on a date...
虽然非常愉快…
...and you're getting along great...
但他的翻译碍手碍脚
... but the guy's translator keeps getting in the way?
瑞秋在房间里吗？
Is Rach in her room?
她还没下班 但叫你打电话给她
She's still at work,but she said to call her.
她又要爽约了？ 她怎么可以这样？
Is she gonna cancel on me again? How could she do this?
我们的周年纪念日怎么办？
What about our anniversary?
我对这件事只知道这么多
This is the extent of my knowledge on the subject.
“打电话给瑞秋”
"Call Rachel."
底下是什么？
What's that on the bottom?
是我的涂鸦 戴高顶礼帽的瓢虫
That's my doodle of a ladybug with a top hat.
很漂亮
She's fancy.
嘿，亲爱的 嗨
-Hey,honey. -Oh,hi.
怎么回事？
how's it going?
嗯，出了个内衣的紧急事件
Well, kind of having an underwear emergency.
哦是吗？有人吓你了吗？让你大笑了吗？
Oh, yeah? What happened? Someone scare you? Make you laugh too hard?
运货出了大问题 我得把这批货弄到
Shipping had a disaster. I've gotta get this order in.
对不起，不过看样子 我要开通宵了
I'm so sorry,but it looks like I'll be here all night.
什么？那我过来好不好？
What? Well,how about I come up there?
不要，亲爱的，拜托 我要处理的事情太多了
No,honey,please. I just have too much to deal with.
反正我今晚要跟塞尔吉出去…
Anyway,I'm going out with Sergei again tonight,and....
你能不能当翻译的女伴
Could you be the translator's date...
这样我们想独处的时候
...so that when we want to be alone...
你们两个可以离开？
...you two can split off?
他长得挺帅的
You know,he's kind of cute.
你说挺帅的是真的很帅？
Like,"really kind of cute"?
还是跟你的朋友 泥浆脊背赖瑞那样的帅？
Or "kind of cute" like your friend Spackle-Back Larry?
别这样说他
Don't call him that.
他叫做泥浆脊背哈瑞
His name is Spackle-Back Harry.
“中央咖啡厅”
我们该出发了
Maybe we should get going.
克萝伊说几点到？
What time did Chloe say to get there?
十点半 现在几点了？
-10:30. -What time is it now?
四点半
4:30.
我们再等等好了
So we'll hang out.
记得她提过 我们三个人那回事吗？
Remember when she brought up that thing about the three of us?
记得很清楚
Yes,vividly.
她是开玩笑的吧？ 我想是的
-She was kidding about that,right? -Yeah,I think so.
我想也是
Yeah,I think so.
老天，如果今晚出现这种场面那就太诡异了
God,it'd be weird if that situation presented itself tonight.
对，我是说…
Yeah,I mean...
我们该怎么办？
...what would we do?
我可不知道
Dude,I don't know.
她是开玩笑的
She was kidding.
她是…
She was....
我们应该订下基本规则 以备不时之需
Just in case,we should have some ground rules.
对，那当然
Yeah. For sure.
最重要的原则就是 “绝对不要张开眼睛”
You probably want the first one to be,"Never open your eyes."
因为最好不要 在你做什么的时候…
Because you don't want to be doing something...
抬头一看，对不对？
...and then look up,right?
看到你不想看的东西
And see something that you don't want to be seeing.
说得好…
Good call. Nice.
等等…
Hold it! Hold it!
万一我的眼睛闭上以后
What if my eyes are closed,and...
我的手在那里…
...and my hand is out there....
好吧，眼睛一直张开
Okay,eyes open at all times!
我们怎么决定…
How do we decide where we...
哪个人…
...you know,each would...
要在…
...you know...
哪里？
... be?
对，你知道 我们可以丢铜板决定
Right. Well,you know,we could flip for it.
我想也是，不过 头和字分别代表什么？
I guess. But like,what's heads and what's tails?
如果连这个都不知道 我也不想跟你一起做了
If you don't know that,I don't want to do this with you.
不…订单就在我面前
No,no. I am looking at a purchase order here...
上面说我们订的 里耶维拉比基尼
...that shows we ordered the Riviera bikini...
各种尺寸和颜色都有
...in a variety of sizes and colors
这跟我穿什么有何相干？
What does it matter what I'm wearing?
可以请你的主管过来吗？ 谢谢
Could I speak to your supervisor? Thank you.
嗨
Hi.
我的天，你来干什么？
My God! What are you doing here?
你说你不能出去，所以…
Well,you said you couldn't go out,so....
你带了野餐篮 真是个好男朋友
You brought a picnic! What a boyfriend.
够了，星期一我要开始化妆
That's it. On Monday,I start wearing makeup.
亲爱的，你很体帖 但我现在有危机
Honey,this is very nice,but I've got a crisis.
但我现在有蒸丸子
But I've got couscous!
亲爱的，对不起 我知道今天是我们周年纪念
Honey,I know it's our anniversary...
但我在电话上跟你说过 我没有时间停下来
... but I told you on the phone,I don't have time to stop.
你不必停下来 我是隐形人，我不在这儿…
You don't have to stop. I'm invisible. I'm not here.
对，可是，我不…
Yeah,but I don't
是谁批准这批货的？
Who approved that order?
我们这里没有马克罗宾逊
Well,there is no Mark Robinson in this office.
打电话给马克 我喜欢马克，你认识他吗？
-Get Mark on the phone! -I love Mark. Do you know him?
让我看看…
Let me check that with what I've got.
038不是本店的号码 是亚特兰大的号码
See,038 is not the number for this store. 038 is Atlanta.
胡椒？
Pepper?
我不用
None for me.
好，对不起
Okay,sorry!
对不起 我刚才说商店号码是错的
Sorry. As I was saying,the store number is wrong.
对不起，可是…
And I'm sorry,but
我的天
Oh,my God!
我待会儿再打给你 山普（“活宝三人组”的其中之一）在我办公室里
I have to call you back. I've got Shemp in my office.
你这是干嘛？ 对不起
-What are you doing? -I'm sorry.
但你电话讲完了 喝杯酒吧？
But somebody's off the phone! How about a glass of wine...
围着炉火对饮 我可以再把火升起来
... by the fire? I can get it going again....
你没有听我说话 我没有空
You're not listening. I don't have time to stop.
你连十分钟都没有？ 我连十分钟都没有
-You don't have 10 minutes? -I don't have 10 minutes!
苏菲，她有十分钟时间吗？ 我说过没有
-Sophie,does she have 10 minutes? -I told you,I don't!
别对我吼 我一个礼拜没见到你了
Don't yell. This is the most I've seen you all week.
听好了，我现在没空理你 我的交货时间到了
Look,I cannot do this right now. I've got a deadline!
回家去，我们回头再说
Go home and we'll talk later.
好，可是等一下… 再见
-Yeah,but wait! -Goodbye!
刚才那个是我们的三洞打孔机
Actually,that's our three-hole punch.
嗨
Hi.
刚才的事…
Look,about what happened earlier
我完全了解 你的压力很大
I completely understand. You were stressed.
我本来要给你机会向我道歉
I was gonna give you a chance to apologize to me.
为你把我赶出办公室而抱歉？
For letting you throw me out of your office?
你没有权利到我办公室来
You had no right coming down to my office.
你不能带着野餐篮 到人家的办公室
You do not bring a picnic basket to somebody's work...
除非这个人是公园管理员
... unless they're a park ranger!
原谅我只想在周年纪念日 跟女朋友在一起
Excuse me for wanting to be with my girl on our anniversary.
老天，我真是混蛋
Boy,what an ass am l!
但我说过我没有时间
But I told you I didn't have the time!
你一直都没时间
Well,you never have the time.
我觉得自己 好像根本没有女朋友
I don't feel like I have a girlfriend anymore.
你是不是要我辞职…
Do you want me to quit my job...
好让你觉得自己有女朋友？
...so you can feel like you have a girlfriend?
我只希望你了解 这只是一份工作
It would nice if you'd realize that it's just a job.
只是一份工作？
Just a job?
这是我一生中第一次 做我觉得有意义的事
It's the first time in my life I'm doing something I care about!
第一次发挥自己的专长
The first time I'm doing something I'm good at!
如果你不了解
If you don't get that
我了解，也为你高兴
I get that,and I'm happy for you.
但我受够跟答录机谈恋爱 我不知道该怎么办
But I'm tired of dating your answering machine! I don't know what to do!
我也不知道
Well,neither do l!
这是因为马克吗？
Is this about Mark?
我的天
Oh,my God!
好，不是
Okay,it's not.
我的老天爷
Oh,my God!
我不能老是跟你 为同一件事情吵架
I cannot keep having this same fight over and over again.
你让我受不了
You're making this too hard.
我让你受不了？ 你要我怎么做？
I'm making this too hard? What should I do?
我不知道…这样吧
I don't know! I don't know! Look...
也许我们应该冷静一下
...maybe we should just take a break!
很好，你说得对 我们冷静一下
Fine,you're right. Let's take a break. Let's cool off.
我们去吃冷冻酸奶吧
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
我们分手吧
A break from us.
过去五年来 在校对方面的进步…
advances in collating in the past five years.
我们进了一台X5000
We just got in an X-5000,you know?
有了X5000 X50看起来就像T71
The X-5000 makes an X-50 look like a T-71.
研究恐龙的人来了
It's the dinosaur guy!
嗨，罗斯 嗨，克萝伊
-Hi,Ross! -Hi,Chloe.
介绍你认识我的朋友
I want you to meet some friends of mine.
他是我的偶像 他要把东西放大四倍
He's my hero. He'll want to blow stuff up 400 percent.
我说我们不印，他说非印不可 结果呢？我们办到了
We say we don't do that. He says,"You gotta." Know what? We did it.
现在有人要放大四倍 我们就说“罗斯影印”
Now anytime anybody wants 400,we just say,"Let's Ross it!"
而且只有一种颜色
And that's the only color that comes in.
克萝伊，你有铜板吗？ 我要买保险套
Yo,Chloe! Do you have a quarter for the condom machine?
你怎么回事？ 今晚不是你的周年纪念日吗？
What are you doing? I thought tonight's your anniversary dinner.
计划略为改变
A little change of plans.
我们打算分手
We're gonna break up instead.
我会说一点法文
And I can speak a little French.
怎么了？我说错了什么？
Why? What did I say?
你刚才问我 今晚要不要跟你上床？
Well,you just asked if I wanted to go to bed with you tonight.
我的天
Oh,my God!
难怪我在莫立斯餐厅（纽约著名的法国餐厅）得到这么好的服务
No wonder I get such great service at Cafe Maurice.
敲…
IKnock,knock,knock.
嗨，麻烦你告诉塞尔吉 我很欣赏…
Hi. Could you please tell Sergei that I was fascinated...
布特罗斯布特罗斯加利（联合国前秘书长）在纽约时报写的文章
...by what Boutros Boutros-Ghali said in the Times?
你没说布特罗斯布特罗斯加利
You didn't say "Boutros Boutros-Ghali."
布特罗斯布特罗斯加利
Boutros Boutros-Ghali.
他说他也是
He says he was too.
有意思
Interesting.
我在想…
So I was wondering
趁你们还没开口说话
Before you get all talky again...
麻烦你告诉塞尔吉
...could you also please tell Sergei...
我很喜欢他的西装
...that I really like his suit.
他说“谢谢你 你今晚很美”
He said,"Thank you. You look pretty tonight.
您的秀发如阳光闪闪发亮 这么说你是个厨师？
Your hair,golden like the sun." So you're a chef?
我打算自己开一间餐厅
I'm also thinking of opening up my own restaurant.
真的？
Really?
跟你说几句悄悄话好吗？
Could I talk to you behind my menu?
你这是干什么？
What are you doing?
我在聊天啊
Well,I was having a conversation.
米夏对你非常有意思 塞尔吉跟我根本说不上话
Misha's so interested in you,Sergei and I haven't been able to talk at all.
你要我安安静静地坐着 听你们三个人说话？
You want me to sit silently,while you three converse?
那太好了，谢谢你
That would be great. Thank you.
嗨，我是马克
Hi. It's Mark.
怎么？我有口臭吗？
What? Is it my breath?
对不起，我以为是别人打来的
Sorry. I just thought you were somebody else.
我只是打来留话的 今晚不是你的周年纪念日吗？
I was just gonna leave a message. Isn't tonight your anniversary dinner?
瑞秋？你没事吧？
Rach? Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah,I'm fine.
你想聊聊吗？我可以过来
You wanna talk? I can come over.
真的不必了，没关系
Really,no. Please. That's okay.
好，我带中国菜过来
All right. I'm coming over with Chinese food.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
是我要吃的
It's for me.
再见
Bye.
你打算怎么办？ 我能怎么办？
-So what'll you do? -What can I do?
对方想分手，就只能分手了
One person wants to break up,you break up.
才不是这么回事 你是男人，打电话去和好
No way. This is you guys. Call her and work it out.
我们刚刚才大吵一架 不用先等一段时间吗？
We just had this huge fight. Don't I have to wait awhile?
又不是刚吃完饭 不能游泳，去打电话
It isn't like swimming after you eat. Pick up the phone!
你知道吃完饭不能游泳 其实是个传言
You know that swimming thing is a myth.
去跟我蓝尼叔叔说吧
Tell that to my Uncle Lenny.
为什么？他怎么了？
Why? What happened to him?
没有怎么了 只不过他非常相信这回事
Nothing. He just really believes in that.
然后我们大吵一架，弄得很僵
Then we got into this big fight It was awful.
我说他把我当公园管理员什么的
I told him he treats me like a park ranger,something....
然后…
And then...
我告诉他我想分手
... I told him I wanted to take a break.
我不想分开
I don't want to take a break.
我真替你难过
I'm sorry.
蛋卷？
Egg roll?
然后我打电话给他 他不在家
And then I called him and he wasn't there.
他大概只是出去了
He's probably just out.
谢谢你，你说的话好有用 你来了可真好
Thank you,that's very helpful. I'm glad you came over.
嗨，是我
Hi,it's me.
很高兴你打来
Oh,I'm so glad you called.
真的？
Really?
这太荒谬了，你不觉得 我们可以沟通吗？
This is crazy. Don't you think we can work on this?
你想喝什么？
What do you want to drink?
那是谁？
Who's that?
没有人
Nobody?
我可以把苹果汁喝光吗？
Is it okay if I finish the apple juice?
那是马克吗？
Is that Mark?
亲爱的，他只是过来…
Honey,he just came over
好，我懂了
Yeah,got it!
嘿，恐龙先生 看看你，好伤心
Hey,Dinosaur Guy! Look at you,so sad.
来跳舞吧
Come dance.
没关系，谢谢你
That's okay. Thanks.
你不必笑 只要跳舞就好了
You don't have to smile. You just have to dance.
我不想跳舞 我想喝酒，好吗？
I don't feel like dancing. I feel like having a drink,okay?
两杯啤酒
Two beers!
好吧，现在是咱们俩跳舞了
Okay, now we're just dancing with each other.
兽医跟我说时候到了
And the vet said it was time.
我在地球的另一端
And so from half a world away...
我母亲把电话拿到它耳朵旁边
...while my mother held the phone to his ear...
我用七种语言…
... I said goodbye to my dog...
跟我的狗说再见
...in seven languages.
给我一张面纸好吗？ 没问题
-Could I have a tissue? -Oh,sure.
希望你不会不小心…
I just hope you don't accidentally...
吸进鼻子里呛死
...suck it up through your nose and choke on it.
塞尔吉为我今晚的言行道歉
Sergei would like to apologize for my behavior tonight.
跟他说“我接受他的道歉”
Well,tell him,"Apology accepted."
真没想到，这么多年来 第一次有人想跟我说话
Unbelievable. For the first time in years,someone wants to talk to me.
但你想他会让我 这么好过吗？当然不会
But do you think he would let me enjoy that? No!
你这个笨外交官 为什么自己不学英文？
You silly diplomat. Why don't you learn some English?
对不起，你的晚餐 不是他付账的吗？
Excuse me,but isn't he paying for your dinner?
人家的狗才刚过世
The man's dog just died.
我辞职了
I have just resigned my post.
你愿不愿意陪我到彩虹厅？
Will you accompany me to the Rainbow Room?
我有外交官折价券
I have diplomatic coupons.
这是我的荣幸
It would be my pleasure.
我的男伴有折价券
My guy has coupons.
你的男伴 连“折价券”都不会讲
Your guy can't even say "coupons."
盘子
Plate.
盘子，对，盘子
Plate! Yes! Plate!
看，我们不需要他们
See,we don't need them.
我喜欢这首歌
I like this song.
你等于已经在跳舞了
Well,you're practically dancing,already.
不如到这里来跳吧？
Why don't you just do it over here?
你已婚了，是吧？
What are you,married?
也无所谓
Because that's okay.
在家…
Oh,be home,be home,be home....
你不在家
You're not home.
还是不笑？
Still no smile?
“未完待续”
美国派小姐
Miss American Pie
美国…
Ameri-can.
这种语言很难学
It's a very hard language.
再来一次
Let's do it again.